Province of St. John the Baptist Franciscans records, 1868-1978 (bulk 1906-1965)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Records of the Province of St. John the Baptist Franciscans, 1868-1978 (bulk 1906-1965)
AZ 500
Franciscans. Province of St. John the Baptist
The collection includes correspondence, financial records, official documents, reports, maps, articles, publications, photographs, postcards, and notes. The bulk of the collection is correspondence and records relating to the establishment and operation of missions and schools, primarily at St. Michaels. These document activity between Franciscan friars, the Navajo population, Catholic organizations, the U. S. Government, and the Land Commissioner of the Santa Fe Pacific Railroad Company. Included are materials on Navajo land allotments, education, language, social conditions, government and church relations, tourism, and origins of the Navajo Tribal Council.
23 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
In 1887, Franciscan friars established St. Michaels Mission in Apache County, Arizona. Its purpose was to bring Catholic doctrine and education to the Navajo Reservation in Arizona and New Mexico. St. Michaels Press was established in 1909, and still produces materials on Navajo and missionary topics.
Organization
This collection is organized into fourteen series:
Series I: St. Michaels Mission, 1898-1978
Series II: Other Southwest Missions, 1899-1975
Series III: Catholic Organizations, 1900-1976
Series IV: Land Records, 1868-1973
Series V: Province of St. John the Baptist, 1897-1976
Series VI: Franciscan Fathers, 1902-1975
Series VII: Catholic Church, 1895-1975
Series VIII: United States Government Offices and Indian Organizations, 1905-1971
Series IX: Indian Education, 1908-1972
Series X: Navaho Indians, 1899-1975
Series XI: Estates, Guardianships and Wills, 1929-1967
Series XII: Father Emanuel Trockur, 1924-1977
Series XIII: Robert L. Wilken's Anselm Weber, O. F. M.: Missionary to the Navaho, 1898-1921, Bruce Publishing Company, 1955, 1949-1973
Series XIV: Oversize Material, 1906-1973
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes correspondence, financial records, official documents, reports, maps, articles, publications, photographs, postcards, and notes. The bulk of the collection is correspondence and records relating to the establishment and operation of missions and schools, primarily at St. Michaels. These document activity between Franciscan friars, the Navajo population, Catholic organizations, the U. S. Government, and the Land Commissioner of the Santa Fe Pacific Railroad Company. Included are materials on Navajo land allotments, education, language, social conditions, government and church relations, tourism, and origins of the Navajo Tribal Council.
Information in publications includes background material relating to the first Navajo dictionary; Kay Bennet's book, The Navajo Saga; Robert L. Wilken's book, Anselm Weber; and the periodical The Padre's Trail. Also present are extracts and complete examples of church publications on Navajo Indians and missionary work. Correspondents include Berard Haile, Leopold Ostermann, and Anselm Weber, other Franciscan Fathers, U.S. government officials, Catholic missionary organizations, Navajo individuals, and others. The papers of Emanuel Trockur include correspondence, writings, and his work with the Confraternity of Christian Doctrine. Photographs represent events, mission buildings, equipment and personnel.
Some material is in German.
Weber, Anslem, 1862-1921; Ostermann, Leopold; Haile, Berard, 1874-1961; Drexel, Katharine Mary, Saint, 1858-1955; Franciscans. Province of St. John the Baptist -- Archives; Confraternity of Christian Doctrine; United States. Bureau of Indian Affairs; Franciscans -- Arizona; Catholic Church -- Southwest, New -- History -- Sources; Navajo Tribal Council; St. Michaels Press; Santa Fe Pacific Railroad Company -- Records and correspondence; Saint Michaels Mission (Ariz.) -- History; United States. General Land Office; Missions -- Southwest, New -- History -- Sources; Navajo Indians -- Education; Navajo Indians -- Government policy; Navajo Indians -- Missions; Navajo Indians -- Land tenure; Navajo language; Navajo Indians -- Photographs; Correspondence; Photographs; Reports
Related Material
For related material see the Berard Haile Papers, AZ 132
Container List
- Series I: St Michaels Mission, 1898-1978
  - Father Anselm Weber, 1899-1978
    - Biographical Material: General. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Biographical Material: Medical. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Father Leopold Ostermann. 1905-1919 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Father Marcellus Troester. 1911-1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Rev. Mother Josephine. 1908 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Various Churches. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Robert E. Morrison, lawyer. 1902-1910 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Regarding Simon Schwemberger. 1903-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Miscellaneous. 1901-1921 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - Manuscript: "The Navajo Indians: A Statement of Facts." (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "The Navajo Indians: A Statement of Facts." (Typescript and printed). (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Extracts from Sendbote. September 1900-November 1919 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      "Die Franziskaner-Mission unter den Navajo-Indianern," published in Der Sendbote des Gottlichen Herzens Jesu. A series of monthly unsigned accounts of mission activity in the Southwest, 1899-1921, by Father Anselm Weber. Father Frederick Hartung filled in from July-November 1900. Father Egbert Fisher did several issues during 1912, 1913 and 1915.
    - Translations from Sendbote. 1899-1919 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Manuscripts and notes: Catholic missionary work. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Manuscripts and notes: Navaho Indians. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Talks. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified material in German and shorthand. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Concerning Father Anselm Weber's old correspondence." 1931-1951 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - School Children's letters to Father Anselm Weber. 1908-1919 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - Other Franciscan Fathers, 1898-1976
    - Father Leopold Ostermann: Biographical Material. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Father Leopold Ostermann: Correspondence with Father Marcellus Troester. 1916-1924 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Father Leopold Ostermann: "Franciscans in the Wilds and Wastes of the Navajo Country." February 1901-October 1909 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Series published in St. Anthony's Messenger. Nos. 1-4, 15-16, 20-26, 28, 41-46, 48-53, 55-57, 60-78, 80-99, 101-102.
    - Father Leopold Ostermann: "Little Mission Stories from Our Own Southwest." March-June 1928 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Articles published in St. Anthony's Messenger.
    - Father Leopold Ostermann: "Navajo Grammar, Part III - Roots of the Navaho Language." (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Father Leopold Ostermann: "Grammatical Notes on the Navajo Language." (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Father Leopold Ostermann: Miscellaneous notes, typescripts, etc. on Navaho Language. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Father Marcellus Troester: Biographical Material. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Father Marcellus Troester: Notebook for Religious Instruction in School. 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Father Marcellus Troester: Letters from his sister, Sister Virginia. 1898-1936 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    - Father Marcellus Troester: Various family letters. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Father Angellus Rom: Biographical Material. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Father Lawrence Rossman: Biographical Material. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous biographical material on various fathers. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Father Jerome Hesse: Correspondence. 1925-1931 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Father Arnold Heinzmann: Biographical Material. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Father Arnold Heinzmann: Correspondence with Franciscan Fathers. 1931-1939 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Father Arnold Heinzmann: Miscellaneous correspondence. 1932-1939 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - FatherWilfrid Humbert: Correspondence. 1935-1955 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Father Anselm Sippel: Correspondence with Franciscan Fathers. 1934-1947 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Father Anselm Sippel: Miscellaneous correspondence. 1933-1948, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Father Bucard Fisher: Correspondence and biographical material. 1951-1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Father John Lanzrath: Correspondence. 1967-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Father Berard Haile: Biographical Material. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Archbishop of Santa Fe, Rudolph A. Gerken: Correspondence. 1933-1938 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence. 1921-1934 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
  - Mission Records, 1901-1977
    - Annual Report to Provincial. 1936/37-1951/52 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report of the Parish to the Provincial. 1932/33-1940/41 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report of Monastery-Residence to the Provincial. 1905/06, 1932/33-1935/36 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Annual Church Report [to the Provincial]. 1941/42-1951/52 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report to the Diocese of Tucson. 1921/22-1939 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Annual Report to the Diocese of Gallup. 1940-1946/47 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Photographs. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Golden Jubilee. October 12, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "Mary Mother of Mankind" Mission Church: Miscellaneous correspondence. 1927-1944 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "Mary Mother of Mankind" Mission Church: Correspondence, Mrs. Philip A. Brennan. 1933-1941 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "Mary Mother of Mankind" Mission Church: Correspondence, Marquette League. 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "Mary Mother of Mankind" Mission Church: Dedication. October 28, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Light and Power: Miscellaneous and general. 1919-1951 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Light and Power: Witte Engine Works, Kansas City, Kan. 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Light and Power: Climax Engineering Co., Clinton, Iowa. 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Light and Power: Forbes-Hewitt Engineering Co., Albuquerque, N. M. 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Light and Power: Westinghouse Electric & Manufacturing Co. 1935-1947 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Light and Power: General Electric Co. 1941-1946 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous maintenance, construction and repair records. 1930-1942 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Employment of Robert Mark as Diesel Generator Operator. 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Historical Material. (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - World War II Ration Books. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Samuel Day and Family: Biographical material and miscellaneous letters. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from Maynard Dixon and J. A. Munk.
    - Unidentified photographs. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Guestbook. 1941-1949 (Box 6)
    - Guestbook of the Chis-Chilly. 1936-1939 (Box 6)
    - Automobiles: General correspondence and records. 1923-1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Automobiles: Insurance including correspondence regarding accidents. 1931-1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Automobiles: War-time rationing of gas, etc. 1942-1944 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Brothers. 1926-1957 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Christmas Cards. 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Films and photo albums. 1933-1937 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Insurance, Commercial Union Assurance Co., Ltd. of London. 1919-1931 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Insurance: Miscellaneous. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Inventory. 1946 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Laundry equipment proposed. 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Letters of recommendation. 1934-1944 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Mission helpers. 1926-1941 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Navajo School for Young Missionaries at St. Michaels. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Paintings by E. A. Burbank. 1937-1938, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Post Office. 1901-1947 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Railroad passes. 1932-1940 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Retreats. 1917-1967 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Schedules. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Tax Exemption, Federal and State. 1918, 1943-1961 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Telephone lists. 1903-1904, 1925, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Construction of St. Michael's Monastery Building: Miscellaneous correspondence. 1929-1943 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Construction of St. Michael's Monastery Building: Construction correspondence, notes, etc. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Construction of St. Michael's Monastery Building: Chas. F. Williams Co., Inc. 1938-1942 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Construction of St. Michael's Monastery Building: Momsen-Dunnegan-Ryan Co. (hardware and plumbing). 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Construction of St. Michael's Monastery Building: Earnest Boardman/Boardman Machine Works. 1938-1942 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Construction of St. Michael's Monastery Building: Gallum Mercantile Co. (plumbing and heating). 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Construction of St. Michael's Monastery Building: Reynolds Electrical and Engineering Co., Inc. (also miscellaneous electrical firms). 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Construction of St. Michael's Monastery Building: Miscellaneous plumbing and heating firms. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Construction of St. Michael's Monastery Building: Miscellaneous lumber firms. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Construction of St. Michael's Monastery Building: Auro Cattaneo (stonework). 1941 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Furnishings. 1941-1943 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Distribution of labor, and related records. 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Payroll records. 1938-1941 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Social security records. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Arizona State Industrial Commission. 1938-1942 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - St. Michael's Indian School: Historical material. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Proposed convent-high school building for the Sisters. 1945-1947 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - St. Michaels Historical Museum: Property transfer, etc. 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - St. Michaels Press: Historical Material. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - St. Michaels Press: Correspondence. 1911-1964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - St. Michaels Press: Copyright Papers. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - St. Michaels Press: Financial records. 1938-1952 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - St. Michaels Press: Monotype machine. 1923-1946 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Franciscan Missions of the Southwest: Correspondence, ads, miscellaneous material. 1915-1922, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Padres' Trail: Correspondence, miscellaneous historical material. 1936-1974 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Padres' Trail: Financial report. June 1, 1947-May 31, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - St. Anthony Messenger: Correspondence. 1914, 1929-1961 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - FatherBerard Haile: Letterbook. 1911 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Includes a financial statement regarding St. Michael Press (July 1, 1911), "Print Shop Plea," letters to FatherAnselm Weber, Bishop Granjon, FatherProvincial Eugene Buttermann.
    - Beneplacita. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Conspectus Generalis Missionum. 1932/33-1935/36 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Missio... Elenchus Informativus Missionariorum. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous statistics and reports. 1913-1954 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous election materials. 1925, 1948-1963 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous census materials. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous materials including unidentified notebooks, assorted photos, and some historical letters. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Two large photographs of St. Michaels Mission. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Financial Records. 1901-1928 (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
    - Financial Records. 1911-1939 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Financial Records. 1912-1952 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Financial Records. 1935-1949 (Box 14, Volume 1-3)
    - Financial Records. 1947-1961 (Box 15, Volume 1-6)
    - Financial Records: McKinley County Bank, Gallup, New Mexico 1909-1937 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Financial Records: Merchants Bank, Gallup, New Mexico 1909-1937 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Financial Records: Various banks. 1912-1938 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Financial Records: Bills for church supplies. 1912-1916 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Financial Records: Bills for publishers and printing. 1912-1919 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Financial Records: Miscellaneous bills. 1905-1916 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Financial Records: Money loaned to Indians. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Financial Records: Promissory notes. 1909-1937 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Financial Records: Receipts. 1904-1910 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous financial records. 1918-1946 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Navaho Saga, 1943-1950
    - Correspondence. November 1948-May 1950 (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
    - Shiya draft. August 9, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Financial records. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Reviews. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Page proof (version not used), condensed selection published in Catholic Mission Digest. June 1950 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Shiya, Thomas: News Releases for the Catholic Relations News Service. 1949 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Shiya, Thomas: Miscellaneous articles. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Shiya, Thomas: Correspondence. 1943, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Navaho Saga (first edition) and final version with title The Franciscan Fathers Present Navaho Saga. 1949 (Box 17)
- Series II: Other Southwest Missions, 1899-1975
  - Chinle, Arizona: Historical material, photographs, notes, etc. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Chinle, Arizona: Annunciation Indian Mission correspondence. 1911-1949 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Crown Point, New Mexico: Miscellaneous material. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Farmington, New Mexico: Miscellaneous material. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Ft. Defiance, Arizona: Our Lady of the Blessed Sacrament Mission historical material, photographs, etc. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Ft. Defiance, Arizona: Our Lady of the Blessed Sacrament Mission correspondence. 1913-1950 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Ft. Defiance, Arizona: Our Lady of the Blessed Sacrament Mission Annual Report to the Provincial. 1932/33-1937/38, 1939/40-1940/41 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Ft. Defiance, Arizona: Utility bills. 1939-1941 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Ft. Defiance, Arizona: Robert G. Arnold biographical material. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Ft. Defiance, Arizona: "Sunday Announcement" book. March 1944-August 1946 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Ft. Wingate, New Mexico: St. Eleanor's Chapel correspondence, Marquette League. 1928-1933 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Ft. Wingate, New Mexico: St. Eleanor's Chapel correspondence, Bureau of Catholic Indian Missions and others. 1929-1932 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Ft. Wingate, New Mexico: Charles H. Burke School correspondence. 1912-1946 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Ft. Wingate, New Mexico: Charles H. Burke School yearbook The Navajo Trail. 1936 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Greasewood, Arizona: Historical material, correspondence. 1926-1938 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Houck, Arizona: Tegakwitha Indian Mission historical material, photographs, notes, etc. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Houck, Arizona: Tegakwitha Indian Mission correspondence, Mother M. Katharine. 1932-1934 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Houck, Arizona: Tegakwitha Indian Mission correspondence. 1905-1973 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Houck, Arizona: Tegakwitha Indian Mission construction bills. 1932-1933 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Houck, Arizona: Tegakwitha Indian Mission The Mai To So, school paper (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Hunter's Point, Arizona: Immaculate Conception Chapel and Day School. 1926-1940 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Keams Canyon, Arizona: St. Joseph Indian Mission historical material, photographs, notes, etc. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Keams Canyon, Arizona: St. Joseph Indian Mission correspondence, Bureau of Catholic Indian Missions. 1926-1929, 1936-1937 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Keams Canyon, Arizona: St. Joseph Indian Mission correspondence, Father Winfred Stauble and Father Arnold Heinzmann. 1931-1939 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Keams Canyon, Arizona: St. Joseph Indian Mission miscellaneous correspondence. 1924-1951 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Keams Canyon, Arizona: St. Joseph Indian Mission Annual Report to the Provincial. 1941/42-1955/56 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Keams Canyon, Arizona: St. Joseph Indian Mission Annual Report to the Diocese of Gallup. 1943/44-1953/54 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Klagetoh, Arizona: St. Anne's Chapel photographs, correspondence. 1930-1941 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Laguna, New Mexico. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Lukachukai, Arizona: St. Isabel Mission historical material, photographs, notes, etc. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Lukachukai, Arizona: St. Isabel Mission general correspondence. 1915-1971 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Lukachukai, Arizona: St. Isabel Mission correspondence, Bureau of Catholic Indian Missions. 1926-1929, 1938 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Lukachukai, Arizona: St. Isabel Mission correspondence, Mother M. Katharine, Sisters of the Blessed Sacrament. 1927-1935 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Lukachukai, Arizona: Construction of First Chapel. 1910 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Manuelito, New Mexico: St. Catherine's Chapel historical material, photographs, notes, etc. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Manuelito, New Mexico: St. Catherine's Chapel correspondence, Marquette League. 1927-1928, 1935-1937 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Manuelito, New Mexico: St. Catherine's Chapel general correspondence. 1928-1947, 1960, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Naschiti, New Mexico: St. Anthony of Padua Chapel. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Nazlini, Arizona: Miscellaneous material. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Pena Blanca, New Mexico: Correspondence, Father Anselm Weber, Father Albert. 1900, 1910, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Pine Springs, Arizona: Historical material, photographs, correspondence. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Pinon Springs, Arizona: Historical material, photographs, correspondence. 1935-1939 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - San Juan Island, New Mexico: Historical material, notes, etc. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - San Juan Island, New Mexico: Correspondence. 1899-1904, 1924 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Sawmill, Arizona: St. Francis Mission historical material, etc. (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Sawmill, Arizona: St. Francis Church Sawmill Catholic News, vol. 1, #1 through vol. 2, #6. January 1955-May 1956 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Shiprock, New Mexico: Christ the King Mission historical material, photographs, notes, etc. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Shiprock, New Mexico: Christ the King Mission correspondence. 1924-1957 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Shiprock, New Mexico: Christ the King Mission correspondence, Archbishop of Santa Fe. 1930, 1934-1935 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Shiprock, New Mexico: Christ the King Mission construction bills. 1933-1935 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Smith Lake, New Mexico: Miscellaneous material. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Tohatchi, New Mexico: Immaculate Conception Mission historical material, photographs, notes, etc. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Tohatchi, New Mexico: Immaculate Conception Mission construction. 1917-1918 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Tohatchi, New Mexico: Immaculate Conception Mission correspondence, Father Adrian Kohl and Father Marcellus Troester. 1922-1925 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Tohatchi, New Mexico: Immaculate Conception Mission miscellaneous correspondence. 1916-1957 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Tsehili, Arizona: Miscellaneous material. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Tuba City, Arizona: Historical material, photographs, notes, etc. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Tuba City, Arizona: Correspondence. 1903-1974 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Wide Ruins, Arizona: Miscellaneous material. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Zuni, New Mexico: St. Anthony's Mission historical material, photographs, notes, etc. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Zuni, New Mexico: St. Anthony's Mission correspondence. 1922, 1931-1940 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Zuni, New Mexico: St. Anthony's Mission school yearbook, A Wona Wi Lona, and The Antonian. 1956, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 16)
- Series III: Catholic Organizations, 1900-1976